Akshay Jain

C26, Aakriti Gardens, Nehru Nagar, Bhopal MP
+91-7974330421, +91-9691256760
iamakshay04@gmail.com
https://in.linkedin.com/in/akshay004
https://azzzey5.github.io/

I have 5+ years of work experience including working with start-ups to global companies. As a consultant I have worked on tagging plans, workspace reporting, visualization, data classification, testing (automated and manual) implementation and honed my ability to align towards customer KPI's and goals. I cross-skill and upskill myself to gather new information and bring out the best in my work.

Experience

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

Senior Consultant/Luminescent Digital (ServicePlan Group Germany), Mumbai, India

- Assisting with enablement & desk-side coaching/training to partners on reports, ad-hoc queries, and future roadmaps.
- Onboarding and setting up the standards and architecture of additional component websites.
- Actively managing the team of young analysts to ensure the smoother delivery of leading KPIs.
- Supporting project estimation process with key contributors to help define scope and prepare statement of work, including tasks, deliverables, milestones, resources, and estimated costs.
- Subject matter expert in the areas of vendor engagement, stakeholder management and project management involving the partners of more than 25 countries.

SEPTEMBER 2018 – JUNE 2021

Senior Web Analytics Consultant/Accenture, Mumbai, India

- Proven abilities to consult with partners to gather business requirements, then translate those requirements into measurable goals and objectives.
- Leading the tag governance using automated web scenarios and audits to find the defect into the implementation.
- Working closely with cross-functional teams (developers, clients etc.) to implement new tracking tags and reporting to meet goals.
- Weekly reporting to clients with the anomalies found on the components.
- Proactively identifying opportunities and making recommendations to improve website effectiveness by drilling into data in order to further profitability and growth.
- Creating hypothesis, highlighting UI bugs on the website architecture to increase the website performance and interactives.
- Implementing third party tags using Adobe Launch.

Tools and Services: Adobe Analytics, Adobe Launch, Observepoint, Columbo, Charles, JIRA and Confluence.

FEBRUARY 2018 - AUGUST 2018

Product Engineer: Frontend/Finly(Jouska Tech), Bangalore, India

As a product engineer I've worked along with the strong tech team to build the frontend of an insight product to monitor the performance of other products used by various clients. My roles at Finly included:

• Consulting with the co-founder to gain the business and technical requirement and modelling the product architecture.

- Interacting with the backend engineers to gain the clean and perfect API data to be populated over the User Interface using Backbone JS.
- Creating intuitive, simple and modern charts to present the visualize the data on User Interface using Google Charts and Charts JS.
- Handling the client requirements for new development into existing tool.
- Creating a perfect User Interface landing pages for campaign user to gain the leads.

Tools and Resources: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Backbone JS, Handlebars, Rubymine, Sublime Text, Bitbucket, Google Charts and Charts JS.

OCTOBER 2016 - DECEMBER 2017

Co-Content Creator/Turban Trap, Bhopal & Delhi, India

As an active co-founder of a youtube channel my roles and responsibilities included:

- Communication and collaboration with music artists.
- Bringing on the new ideas to increase the reach on various platform.
- Creating visualizer for the music and uploading the music video on various platform.

Tools and Resources: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects and Adobe Premiere Pro.

DECEMBER 2015 - SEPETEMBER 2016

Frontend Developer/Frugal Testing, Hyderabad, India

As a frontend developer and being the very first employee of the company my roles and responsibilities included:

- Analyzing the competitive landscape and challenges to resolve those from our product.
- Creating the basic architecture of the web application using HTML, CSS, JS and jQuery.
- Upgrading the web app by adding a dashboard to show the real-time reports to the user.
- Designing campaign emails and landing pages for new customers.
- Designing the banners, cards and standees to showcase in startup conferences.
- Actively pitching the product to other business leaders at startup conferences.

Tools and Resources: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Sublime, Google Charts, Highcharts, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premier Pro, Adobe After Effects.

Certifications

Adobe Analytics Architect Master – AD0-E207



Education

JUNE 2015

Bachelor of Engineering/Rajiv Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal, India

APRIL 2011

Intermediate/Sharda Vidya Mandir, Bhopal, India

Activities

Travel • Cricket • Football • Athletics